[
    {
        "question": "1. What is Web API and why we use it ?",
        "answer": "Web API (Application Programming Interface), as the name suggests, is an API that can be accessed over the Web using the HTTP protocol. It is basically considered the best platform for revealing or uncovering data and services to various different services. It is a tool that can be used to push data to a server and can be accessed by server code. It can be built or developed using various technologies like java, ASP.NET, etc.   Web API Uses:  Web API Uses: It contains additional layers that simply standardize communications and provide different options on how to format input and output.\nIt can be used with ASP.NET MVC and different types of web applications such as ASP.NET WebForms.\nIf one wants to create resource-oriented services, then Web API services are considered the best.\nIt also helps to develop REST-ful services and SOAP-based services. It contains additional layers that simply standardize communications and provide different options on how to format input and output. It can be used with ASP.NET MVC and different types of web applications such as ASP.NET WebForms. If one wants to create resource-oriented services, then Web API services are considered the best. It also helps to develop REST-ful services and SOAP-based services.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "2. What is MVC? Write difference between MVC and Web API?",
        "answer": "MVC (Model, View, and Controller) is basically an application design model that comprises three interconnect parts I.e., model, view, and controller. It allows coders to factor out different components of the application and update them more easily. It is mostly used for developing model user interfaces. Its main purpose is to display patterns in structure for keeping display and data separate to enable both of them to change without affecting others. MVC MVC MVC Web API\nIt can be used to build Web applications that reply as both data and views. It is used to build HTTP services that reply only as data.\nIt returns data in JSON format by using JSONResult. It returns data in different formats such as JSON, XML, etc.\nIt supports content negotiation, self-hosting. It does not support content negotiation, self-hosting.\nIt is not able to build REST-full services. It is very helpful in creating REST-full services.\nIt returns a view (HTML). It returns REST responses. MVC Web API\nIt can be used to build Web applications that reply as both data and views. It is used to build HTTP services that reply only as data.\nIt returns data in JSON format by using JSONResult. It returns data in different formats such as JSON, XML, etc.\nIt supports content negotiation, self-hosting. It does not support content negotiation, self-hosting.\nIt is not able to build REST-full services. It is very helpful in creating REST-full services.\nIt returns a view (HTML). It returns REST responses. MVC Web API MVC Web API MVC Web API It can be used to build Web applications that reply as both data and views. It is used to build HTTP services that reply only as data.\nIt returns data in JSON format by using JSONResult. It returns data in different formats such as JSON, XML, etc.\nIt supports content negotiation, self-hosting. It does not support content negotiation, self-hosting.\nIt is not able to build REST-full services. It is very helpful in creating REST-full services.\nIt returns a view (HTML). It returns REST responses. It can be used to build Web applications that reply as both data and views. It is used to build HTTP services that reply only as data. It can be used to build Web applications that reply as both data and views. It is used to build HTTP services that reply only as data. It returns data in JSON format by using JSONResult. It returns data in different formats such as JSON, XML, etc. It returns data in JSON format by using JSONResult. It returns data in different formats such as JSON, XML, etc. It supports content negotiation, self-hosting. It does not support content negotiation, self-hosting. It supports content negotiation, self-hosting. It does not support content negotiation, self-hosting. It is not able to build REST-full services. It is very helpful in creating REST-full services. It is not able to build REST-full services. It is very helpful in creating REST-full services. It returns a view (HTML). It returns REST responses. It returns a view (HTML). It returns REST responses.  ",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "3. How to register an exception filter globally?",
        "answer": "One can register exception filter globally using following code:\nGlobalConfiguration.Configuration.Filters.Add (new MyTestCustomerStore.NotImplExceptionFilterAttribute());  GlobalConfiguration.Configuration.Filters.Add (new MyTestCustomerStore.NotImplExceptionFilterAttribute()); ",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "4. How to handle errors in Web API?",
        "answer": "Web API generally provides greater flexibility in terms of handling errors. Exception handling is a technique that is used to handle run-time errors in application code. One can use HttpResponseException, HttpError, Exception filters, register exception filters, Exception handlers to handle errors. Exception filter can be used to identify unhandled exceptions on actions or controllers, exception handlers can be used to identify any type of unhandled exception application-wide, and HttpResponseException can be used when there is the possibility of an exception.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "5. Who can consume Web API?",
        "answer": "A large range of clients such as browsers, mobile devices, iPhone, etc., include or consume web API. It is also good for using along native applications that require web services but not SOAP support. It can also be consumed by any client that supports HTTP verbs such as GET, DELETE, POST, PUT.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "6. What are Web API filters?",
        "answer": "Filters are basically used to add extra logic at different levels of Web API framework request processing.  Different types of Web API filters are available as given below: Authentication Filter: It handles authentication and authenticates HTTP requests. It also helps to authenticate user detail. It checks the identity of the user.\nAuthorization Filter: It handles authorization. It runs before controller action. This filter is used to check whether or not a user is authenticated. If the user is not authenticated, then it returns an HTTP status code 401 without invoking the action.\nAuthorizeAttribute is a built-in authorization filter provided by Web API.\nAction Filter: It is attributing that one can apply to controller action or entire controller. It is used to add extra logic before or after controller action executes. It is simply a way to add extra functionality to Web API services.\nException Filter: It is used to handle exceptions that are unhandled in Web API. It is used whenever controller actions throw an unhandled exception that is not HttpResponseException. It will implement an “IExceptionFilter” interface.\nOverride Filter: It is used to exclude specific action methods or controllers from the global filter or controller level filter. It is simply used to modify the behavior of other filters for individual action methods. Authentication Filter: It handles authentication and authenticates HTTP requests. It also helps to authenticate user detail. It checks the identity of the user. Authentication Filter: Authorization Filter: It handles authorization. It runs before controller action. This filter is used to check whether or not a user is authenticated. If the user is not authenticated, then it returns an HTTP status code 401 without invoking the action. Authorization Filter: AuthorizeAttribute is a built-in authorization filter provided by Web API. AuthorizeAttribute Action Filter: It is attributing that one can apply to controller action or entire controller. It is used to add extra logic before or after controller action executes. It is simply a way to add extra functionality to Web API services. Action Filter Exception Filter: It is used to handle exceptions that are unhandled in Web API. It is used whenever controller actions throw an unhandled exception that is not HttpResponseException. It will implement an “IExceptionFilter” interface. Exception Filter Override Filter: It is used to exclude specific action methods or controllers from the global filter or controller level filter. It is simply used to modify the behavior of other filters for individual action methods. Override Filter  ",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "7. What is XML and JSON?",
        "answer": "XML (Extensible Markup Language): XML It is especially designed to store and transport data.\nIt is similar to HTML but is more flexible than HTML because it allows users to create their own custom tags.\nIt is used for representing structured information such as documents, data, configuration, etc. It is especially designed to store and transport data. It is similar to HTML but is more flexible than HTML because it allows users to create their own custom tags. It is used for representing structured information such as documents, data, configuration, etc. JSON (JavaScript Object Notation):  JSON It is a lightweight format designed to store and transport data.\nIt is easier to understand and is a standard text-based format used for representing structured data based on JavaScript object syntax.\nIt is faster and easier to use. It is a lightweight format designed to store and transport data. It is easier to understand and is a standard text-based format used for representing structured data based on JavaScript object syntax. It is faster and easier to use.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "8. Which of the following Open-source libraries is used by WEB API for JSON serialization?",
        "answer": "Json.NET library is generally used by Web API for JSON serialization.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "9. Explain media type formatters.",
        "answer": "In web API, media type formatters are classes that are responsible for serialization data. Here, serialization generally means a process of translating data into a format that can be transmitted and reconstructed later.  Because of serializing request/response data, Web API can understand request data format in a better way and send data in a format that the client expects. It simply specifies data that is being transferred among client and server in HTTP response or request. Media Type Formatter Class MIME Type Description\nJsonMediaTypeFormatter application/json, text/json Handles JSON format\nXmlMediaTypeFormatter application/xml, text/json Handles XML format\nFormUrlEncodedMediaTypeFormatter application/x-www-form-urlencoded Handles HTM form URL-encoded data\nJQueryMvcFormUrlEncodedFormatter application/x-www-form-urlencoded Handles model-bound HTML form URL-encoded data Media Type Formatter Class MIME Type Description\nJsonMediaTypeFormatter application/json, text/json Handles JSON format\nXmlMediaTypeFormatter application/xml, text/json Handles XML format\nFormUrlEncodedMediaTypeFormatter application/x-www-form-urlencoded Handles HTM form URL-encoded data\nJQueryMvcFormUrlEncodedFormatter application/x-www-form-urlencoded Handles model-bound HTML form URL-encoded data Media Type Formatter Class MIME Type Description Media Type Formatter Class MIME Type Description Media Type Formatter Class MIME Type Description JsonMediaTypeFormatter application/json, text/json Handles JSON format\nXmlMediaTypeFormatter application/xml, text/json Handles XML format\nFormUrlEncodedMediaTypeFormatter application/x-www-form-urlencoded Handles HTM form URL-encoded data\nJQueryMvcFormUrlEncodedFormatter application/x-www-form-urlencoded Handles model-bound HTML form URL-encoded data JsonMediaTypeFormatter application/json, text/json Handles JSON format JsonMediaTypeFormatter application/json, text/json Handles JSON format XmlMediaTypeFormatter application/xml, text/json Handles XML format XmlMediaTypeFormatter application/xml, text/json Handles XML format FormUrlEncodedMediaTypeFormatter application/x-www-form-urlencoded Handles HTM form URL-encoded data FormUrlEncodedMediaTypeFormatter application/x-www-form-urlencoded Handles HTM form URL-encoded data JQueryMvcFormUrlEncodedFormatter application/x-www-form-urlencoded Handles model-bound HTML form URL-encoded data JQueryMvcFormUrlEncodedFormatter application/x-www-form-urlencoded Handles model-bound HTML form URL-encoded data  ",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "10. Why is the Web API important?",
        "answer": "Web API is generally considered as a service that basically provides us information or data from the server. It is very important because of the following reasons: It is used to provide an interface for websites and client applications to have access to data.\nIt can also be used to access data from the database and save data back to the database.\nIt supports different text formats such as XML, JSON, etc.\nIt is suitable or compatible with any type of browser and any type of device like mobile, desktop, web, etc.\nIt uses low bandwidth such as XML or JSON data, etc., and is therefore considered good for devices that have limited bandwidth such as smartphones, etc.\nFrom a business point of view, web API is more applicable for UI/UX, increases interest in the company’s product and services, increases website traffic. It is used to provide an interface for websites and client applications to have access to data. It can also be used to access data from the database and save data back to the database. It supports different text formats such as XML, JSON, etc. It is suitable or compatible with any type of browser and any type of device like mobile, desktop, web, etc. It uses low bandwidth such as XML or JSON data, etc., and is therefore considered good for devices that have limited bandwidth such as smartphones, etc. From a business point of view, web API is more applicable for UI/UX, increases interest in the company’s product and services, increases website traffic.  ",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "11. What are the main return types supported in Web API?",
        "answer": "It does not have any specific data type. It can return data of any type depending upon the business requirement. There are many HTTP methods like GET, POST, PUT, etc., which can return data in different formats depending upon the use case.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "12. What is the difference between Web API and WCF?",
        "answer": "WCF (Windows Communication Foundation): It is a framework used for developing SOAP (Service-oriented applications). This framework is used for developing, configuring, and deploying, or implementing network-distributed services. \n\nWeb API: It is an application programming interface for both web browsers and web servers. Browser API simply extends or increases the functionality of web browsers whereas Server API simply extends or increases the functionality of web server. WCF   Web API Web API WCF\nIt is used to develop both SOAP-based services and RESTful services. It is used to deploy only SOAP-based services.\nIt supports various MVC features such as routing, model binding, etc. It does not support any MVC features.\nIt only supports HTTP protocol. It supports various protocols such as HTTP, UDP, custom transport.\nIt is considered best for developing RESTFUL services. It supports only limited RESTFUL services.\nIt is good when one wants to expose an expensive range of clients such as iPhones, browsers, mobile phones, tablets, etc. It is good for creating services that uses expedite transport channels such as TCP, UDP, Named pipes, etc.\nIt offers support for UTF-8 encoding format. It offers TEXT, Binary encoding support, MTOM (Message Transmission Optimization Mechanism), etc. Web API WCF\nIt is used to develop both SOAP-based services and RESTful services. It is used to deploy only SOAP-based services.\nIt supports various MVC features such as routing, model binding, etc. It does not support any MVC features.\nIt only supports HTTP protocol. It supports various protocols such as HTTP, UDP, custom transport.\nIt is considered best for developing RESTFUL services. It supports only limited RESTFUL services.\nIt is good when one wants to expose an expensive range of clients such as iPhones, browsers, mobile phones, tablets, etc. It is good for creating services that uses expedite transport channels such as TCP, UDP, Named pipes, etc.\nIt offers support for UTF-8 encoding format. It offers TEXT, Binary encoding support, MTOM (Message Transmission Optimization Mechanism), etc. Web API WCF Web API WCF Web API WCF It is used to develop both SOAP-based services and RESTful services. It is used to deploy only SOAP-based services.\nIt supports various MVC features such as routing, model binding, etc. It does not support any MVC features.\nIt only supports HTTP protocol. It supports various protocols such as HTTP, UDP, custom transport.\nIt is considered best for developing RESTFUL services. It supports only limited RESTFUL services.\nIt is good when one wants to expose an expensive range of clients such as iPhones, browsers, mobile phones, tablets, etc. It is good for creating services that uses expedite transport channels such as TCP, UDP, Named pipes, etc.\nIt offers support for UTF-8 encoding format. It offers TEXT, Binary encoding support, MTOM (Message Transmission Optimization Mechanism), etc. It is used to develop both SOAP-based services and RESTful services. It is used to deploy only SOAP-based services. It is used to develop both SOAP-based services and RESTful services. It is used to deploy only SOAP-based services. It supports various MVC features such as routing, model binding, etc. It does not support any MVC features. It supports various MVC features such as routing, model binding, etc. It does not support any MVC features. It only supports HTTP protocol. It supports various protocols such as HTTP, UDP, custom transport. It only supports HTTP protocol. It supports various protocols such as HTTP, UDP, custom transport. It is considered best for developing RESTFUL services. It supports only limited RESTFUL services. It is considered best for developing RESTFUL services. It supports only limited RESTFUL services. It is good when one wants to expose an expensive range of clients such as iPhones, browsers, mobile phones, tablets, etc. It is good for creating services that uses expedite transport channels such as TCP, UDP, Named pipes, etc. It is good when one wants to expose an expensive range of clients such as iPhones, browsers, mobile phones, tablets, etc. It is good for creating services that uses expedite transport channels such as TCP, UDP, Named pipes, etc. It offers support for UTF-8 encoding format. It offers TEXT, Binary encoding support, MTOM (Message Transmission Optimization Mechanism), etc. It offers support for UTF-8 encoding format. It offers TEXT, Binary encoding support, MTOM (Message Transmission Optimization Mechanism), etc.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "13. Why to choose Web API over WCF?",
        "answer": "Web API is considered the best choice over WCF because of the following reasons: Web API uses all features of HTTP such as URIs, request/response headers, caching, versioning, various content formats, etc.\nOne does not have to define or explain any extra config setting for different devices in Web API.\nWeb API uses different text formats including XML because of which it is faster and more preferred for lightweight services.\nWeb API also supports MVC features whereas WCF does not support MVC features.\nWeb API provides more flexibility as compared to WCF.\nWeb API uses standard security like token authentication, basic authentication, etc., to provide secure service whereas WCF uses WS-I standard to provide secure service. Web API uses all features of HTTP such as URIs, request/response headers, caching, versioning, various content formats, etc. One does not have to define or explain any extra config setting for different devices in Web API. Web API uses different text formats including XML because of which it is faster and more preferred for lightweight services. Web API also supports MVC features whereas WCF does not support MVC features. Web API provides more flexibility as compared to WCF. Web API uses standard security like token authentication, basic authentication, etc., to provide secure service whereas WCF uses WS-I standard to provide secure service.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "14. What are the advantages of using Rest in Web API?",
        "answer": "REST is very important and beneficial in Web API because of the following reasons: It allows less data transfer between client and server.\nIt is easy to use and lightweight.\nIt provides more flexibility.\nIt also handles and controls various types of calls, returning various data formats.\nIt is considered best for using it in mobile apps because it makes less data transfer between client and server.\nIt uses simple HTTP calls for inter-machine communication rather than using more complex options like CORBA, COM+, SOAP, or RPC. It allows less data transfer between client and server. It is easy to use and lightweight. It provides more flexibility. It also handles and controls various types of calls, returning various data formats. It is considered best for using it in mobile apps because it makes less data transfer between client and server. It uses simple HTTP calls for inter-machine communication rather than using more complex options like CORBA, COM+, SOAP, or RPC.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "15. Web API supports which protocol?",
        "answer": "Web API generally supports only HTTP protocol.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "16. What is Web API 2.0?",
        "answer": "It is basically an enhanced and modified feature of Web API. This new version supports various new features as given below: New Routing Attribute\nSecure ASP.NET Web API using OAuth 2.0\nSupport for Cross-Origin requests using CORS\nIHttpActionResult return type\nSupport for $expand, $select in OData Service New Routing Attribute Secure ASP.NET Web API using OAuth 2.0 Support for Cross-Origin requests using CORS IHttpActionResult return type Support for $expand, $select in OData Service $ $ Because of all the new features of Web API 2.0, it is considered an optimal choice and suitable development model that makes it easier to develop RESTful services interfaces to different clients running on various platforms. It also supports configuring routes in the Web API method or controller level.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "17. What is REST and SOAP? What is different between them?",
        "answer": "REST (Representational State Transfer):  It is a new and improved form of web service. It describes the architectural style of networked systems. It does not require greater bandwidth when requests are sent to the server. It just includes JSON message. For example: REST (Representational State Transfer) {\"city\":\"Mumbai\",\"state\":\"Maharashtra\"} {\"city\":\"Mumbai\",\"state\":\"Maharashtra\"} SOAP (Simple Object Access Protocol): It is a simple and lightweight protocol that is generally used for exchanging structured and typed information on the Web. It works mostly with HTTP and RPC (Remote Procedure Call). This protocol is mainly used for B2B applications one can define a data contract with it. SOAP messages are heavier in content and therefore use greater bandwidth. SOAP (Simple Object Access Protocol) For example: <?xml version=\"1.0\"?>\n<SOAP-ENV:Envelope xmlns:SOAP-ENV=\"http://www.w3.org/2001/12/soap-envelope\" SOAP-ENV:encodingStyle=\" http://www.w3.org/2001/12/soap-encoding\">\n<soap:Body>\n<Demo.guru99WebService xmlns=\"http://tempuri.org/\">   <EmployeeID>int</EmployeeID>   \n</Demo.guru99WebService> \n</soap:Body>\n</SOAP-ENV:Envelope> <?xml version=\"1.0\"?>\n<SOAP-ENV:Envelope xmlns:SOAP-ENV=\"http://www.w3.org/2001/12/soap-envelope\" SOAP-ENV:encodingStyle=\" http://www.w3.org/2001/12/soap-encoding\">\n<soap:Body>\n<Demo.guru99WebService xmlns=\"http://tempuri.org/\">   <EmployeeID>int</EmployeeID>   \n</Demo.guru99WebService> \n</soap:Body>\n</SOAP-ENV:Envelope> REST SOAP\nIt is basically an architectural pattern. It is basically a messaging protocol.\nIt usually works with various text formats such as plain text, HTML, JSON, XML, etc. It only works with XML formats.\nIt is totally stateless. It has some specifications for both stateless and stateful implementation.\nIts performance is faster as compared to SOAP. Its performance is slower as compared to REST.\nIt uses XML and JSON to send and receive data. It uses WSDL (Web Service Description Language) for communication among consumers or users and providers.\nREST has to resend transfer whenever it determines any errors. SOAP includes built-in error handling for communications errors using WS-ReliableMessaging specification.\nIt calls services using the URL path. It calls services by calling RPC (Remote Procedure Call) method. REST SOAP\nIt is basically an architectural pattern. It is basically a messaging protocol.\nIt usually works with various text formats such as plain text, HTML, JSON, XML, etc. It only works with XML formats.\nIt is totally stateless. It has some specifications for both stateless and stateful implementation.\nIts performance is faster as compared to SOAP. Its performance is slower as compared to REST.\nIt uses XML and JSON to send and receive data. It uses WSDL (Web Service Description Language) for communication among consumers or users and providers.\nREST has to resend transfer whenever it determines any errors. SOAP includes built-in error handling for communications errors using WS-ReliableMessaging specification.\nIt calls services using the URL path. It calls services by calling RPC (Remote Procedure Call) method. REST SOAP REST SOAP REST SOAP It is basically an architectural pattern. It is basically a messaging protocol.\nIt usually works with various text formats such as plain text, HTML, JSON, XML, etc. It only works with XML formats.\nIt is totally stateless. It has some specifications for both stateless and stateful implementation.\nIts performance is faster as compared to SOAP. Its performance is slower as compared to REST.\nIt uses XML and JSON to send and receive data. It uses WSDL (Web Service Description Language) for communication among consumers or users and providers.\nREST has to resend transfer whenever it determines any errors. SOAP includes built-in error handling for communications errors using WS-ReliableMessaging specification.\nIt calls services using the URL path. It calls services by calling RPC (Remote Procedure Call) method. It is basically an architectural pattern. It is basically a messaging protocol. It is basically an architectural pattern. It is basically a messaging protocol. It usually works with various text formats such as plain text, HTML, JSON, XML, etc. It only works with XML formats. It usually works with various text formats such as plain text, HTML, JSON, XML, etc. It only works with XML formats. It is totally stateless. It has some specifications for both stateless and stateful implementation. It is totally stateless. It has some specifications for both stateless and stateful implementation. Its performance is faster as compared to SOAP. Its performance is slower as compared to REST. Its performance is faster as compared to SOAP. Its performance is slower as compared to REST. It uses XML and JSON to send and receive data. It uses WSDL (Web Service Description Language) for communication among consumers or users and providers. It uses XML and JSON to send and receive data. It uses WSDL (Web Service Description Language) for communication among consumers or users and providers. REST has to resend transfer whenever it determines any errors. SOAP includes built-in error handling for communications errors using WS-ReliableMessaging specification. REST has to resend transfer whenever it determines any errors. SOAP includes built-in error handling for communications errors using WS-ReliableMessaging specification. It calls services using the URL path. It calls services by calling RPC (Remote Procedure Call) method. It calls services using the URL path. It calls services by calling RPC (Remote Procedure Call) method.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "18. What is different between REST API and RESTful API?",
        "answer": "REST (Representation State Transfer) API:  It is basically an architectural style that makes productive use of existing technology and protocols of the web. It is a set of rules that developers need to follow when they develop their API or services that are scalable. It is used with HTTP protocol using its verbs such as GET, DELETE, POST, PUT. \nRESTful API: It is simply referred to as web services executing such as architecture. REST API  RESTful API REST API RESTful API\nREST is an architectural pattern used for creating web services. RESTful API is used to implement that pattern.\nThe data format of REST is based on HTTP. The data format of RESTful is based on JSON, HTTP, and Text.\nWorking of URL is based on request and response. Working of RESTful is based on REST applications.\nIt is more user-friendly and highly adaptable to all business enterprises and IT. It is too flexible.\nIt is required to develop APIs that allow interaction among clients and servers. It simply follows REST infrastructure that provides interoperability among different systems on the whole network. REST API RESTful API\nREST is an architectural pattern used for creating web services. RESTful API is used to implement that pattern.\nThe data format of REST is based on HTTP. The data format of RESTful is based on JSON, HTTP, and Text.\nWorking of URL is based on request and response. Working of RESTful is based on REST applications.\nIt is more user-friendly and highly adaptable to all business enterprises and IT. It is too flexible.\nIt is required to develop APIs that allow interaction among clients and servers. It simply follows REST infrastructure that provides interoperability among different systems on the whole network. REST API RESTful API REST API RESTful API REST API RESTful API REST is an architectural pattern used for creating web services. RESTful API is used to implement that pattern.\nThe data format of REST is based on HTTP. The data format of RESTful is based on JSON, HTTP, and Text.\nWorking of URL is based on request and response. Working of RESTful is based on REST applications.\nIt is more user-friendly and highly adaptable to all business enterprises and IT. It is too flexible.\nIt is required to develop APIs that allow interaction among clients and servers. It simply follows REST infrastructure that provides interoperability among different systems on the whole network. REST is an architectural pattern used for creating web services. RESTful API is used to implement that pattern. REST is an architectural pattern used for creating web services. RESTful API is used to implement that pattern. The data format of REST is based on HTTP. The data format of RESTful is based on JSON, HTTP, and Text. The data format of REST is based on HTTP. The data format of RESTful is based on JSON, HTTP, and Text. Working of URL is based on request and response. Working of RESTful is based on REST applications. Working of URL is based on request and response. Working of RESTful is based on REST applications. It is more user-friendly and highly adaptable to all business enterprises and IT. It is too flexible. It is more user-friendly and highly adaptable to all business enterprises and IT. It is too flexible. It is required to develop APIs that allow interaction among clients and servers. It simply follows REST infrastructure that provides interoperability among different systems on the whole network. It is required to develop APIs that allow interaction among clients and servers. It simply follows REST infrastructure that provides interoperability among different systems on the whole network.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "1. What is ASP.NET Web API?",
        "answer": "ASP stands for Active server pages. ASP.NET is an updated version of legacy ASP. It is a framework that is used for developing HTTP services to provide responses to client requests. It can be accessed in different applications on different platforms. It is provided by Microsoft open-source technology for developing and consuming HTTP-based services on top of .NET Framework.  It is very easy to build HTTP services using ASP.NET Web API. These services can be used by different clients as given below: Desktop Applications\nMobile Applications\nIOTs\nBrowsers Desktop Applications Mobile Applications IOTs Browsers",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "2. What are the advantages of using ASP.NET Web API?",
        "answer": "Some of the core advantages of using ASP.NET Web API are given below: It provides the best platform for developing RESTful applications on .NET Framework.\nIt works the same way that HTTP works with help of HTTP verbs such as GET, POST, PUT, DELETE for all crud operations.\nIt provides enough flexibility in Web API creation.\nIt completely supports routing.\nIt also supports model binding, validation, Odata (Open Data Protocol) that allows creation and consumption of RESTful APIs.\nIt has the ability to develop custom help and test pages with help of ApiExplorer.\nOne can develop non-SOAP-based services such as plain XML, JSON strings, etc.\nIt also increases the TDD (Test Data-Driven) approach in the development of RESTful services. It provides the best platform for developing RESTful applications on .NET Framework. It works the same way that HTTP works with help of HTTP verbs such as GET, POST, PUT, DELETE for all crud operations. It provides enough flexibility in Web API creation. It completely supports routing. It also supports model binding, validation, Odata (Open Data Protocol) that allows creation and consumption of RESTful APIs. It has the ability to develop custom help and test pages with help of ApiExplorer. One can develop non-SOAP-based services such as plain XML, JSON strings, etc. It also increases the TDD (Test Data-Driven) approach in the development of RESTful services.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "3. What are new features used in ASP.NET Web API 2.0",
        "answer": "ASP.NET Web API includes a number of new exciting features as given below: Attribute Routing\nCORS (Cross-Origin Resource Sharing)\nOWIN (Open Web Interface for .NET) self-hosting\nIHttpActionResult\nWeb API OData Attribute Routing CORS (Cross-Origin Resource Sharing) OWIN (Open Web Interface for .NET) self-hosting IHttpActionResult Web API OData",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "4. What is the use of HttpResponseMessage?",
        "answer": "It is used to set response values such as header and status control. It simply allows us to work with HTTP protocol. It represents HTTP response messages that encapsulate data and status code. // GetEmployee action \npublic HttpResponseMessage GetEmployee(int id) \n{     \n     Employee emp = EmployeeContext.Employees.Where(e => e.Id == id).FirstOrDefault(); \n     if (emp != null) \n      { \n               return Request.CreateResponse<Employee>(HttpStatusCode.OK, emp);     \n      }     else     \n      { \n               return Request.CreateErrorResponse(HttpStatusCode.NotFound, \"Employee Not Found\"); \n      } \n} // GetEmployee action \npublic HttpResponseMessage GetEmployee(int id) \n{     \n     Employee emp = EmployeeContext.Employees.Where(e => e.Id == id).FirstOrDefault(); \n     if (emp != null) \n      { \n               return Request.CreateResponse<Employee>(HttpStatusCode.OK, emp);     \n      }     else     \n      { \n               return Request.CreateErrorResponse(HttpStatusCode.NotFound, \"Employee Not Found\"); \n      } \n}",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "5. What is the difference between ApiController and Controller?",
        "answer": "ApiController: It is used to return data that is arranged in series and then sent to the client. ApiController: public class TweetsController : ApiController\n{\n         // GET: /Api/Tweets/  \n        public List<Tweet> Get()\n      {\n          return Twitter.GetTweets();\n       }\n} public class TweetsController : ApiController\n{\n         // GET: /Api/Tweets/  \n        public List<Tweet> Get()\n      {\n          return Twitter.GetTweets();\n       }\n} Controller: It is used to provide normal views. Controller: public class TweetsController : Controller \n{  \n        // GET: /Tweets/  [HttpGet]  public ActionResult Index() \n       {    \n           return Json(Twitter.GetTweets(), JsonRequestBehavior.AllowGet);  \n       }\n} public class TweetsController : Controller \n{  \n        // GET: /Tweets/  [HttpGet]  public ActionResult Index() \n       {    \n           return Json(Twitter.GetTweets(), JsonRequestBehavior.AllowGet);  \n       }\n}",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "6. What do you mean by Caching and What are its types?",
        "answer": "Caching is basically a technique or process of storing data somewhere or in the cache for future requests. The cache is a temporary storage area. Caching keeps all frequently or recently accessed files or data in the cache memory and accesses them from the cache itself rather than actual address of data or files. The cache interface simply improves the storage mechanism for request/response object pairs that are being cached.\n\nAdvantages of Caching:   Advantages of Caching: It is considered the best solution to ensure that data is served where it is needed to be served that too at a high level of efficiency which is best for both client and server.\nIt delivers web objects faster to the end-user.\nIt reduces load time on the website server.\nIt leads to faster execution of any process.\nIt decreases network costs. It is considered the best solution to ensure that data is served where it is needed to be served that too at a high level of efficiency which is best for both client and server. It delivers web objects faster to the end-user. It reduces load time on the website server. It leads to faster execution of any process. It decreases network costs. Types of Caching:\nThere are basically three types of caching as given below: Types of Caching:  Page Caching\nData Caching\nFragment Caching Page Caching Data Caching Fragment Caching",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "7. WCF is replaced by ASP.NET Web API. True/False?",
        "answer": "WCF: It is a framework used for developing SOAP (Service Oriented Applications Protocols). It also supports various transport protocols as given above. \nASP.NET Web API: It is a framework used for developing non-SOAP-based services. It is limited to HTTP-based services.\n\nNo, it's not true that ASP.NET Web API has replaced WCF. WCF was generally developed to develop SOAP-based services. ASP.NET Web API is a new way to develop non-SOAP-based services such as XML, JSON, etc. WCF is still considered a better choice if one has their service using HTTP as the transport and they want to move to some other transport like TCP, NetTCP, MSMQ, etc. WCF also allows one-way communication or duplex communication. WCF:  ASP.NET Web API:  ",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "8. What are the main return types supported in ASP. Net Web API?",
        "answer": "It supports the following return types: HttpResponseMessage\nIHttpActionResult\nVoid\nOther types such as string, int, etc. HttpResponseMessage IHttpActionResult Void Other types such as string, int, etc.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "9. What is ASP.NET Web API routing?",
        "answer": "Routing is the most important part of ASP.NET Web API. Routing is a way how Web API matches a URI to an action. It is basically a process that decides which action and controller should be called. The controller is basically a class that handles all HTTP requests. All public methods of controllers are basically known as action methods or just actions. Whenever a Web API framework receives any type of request, it routes that request to action. There are basically two ways to implement routing in Web API as given below:\nConvention-based routing: Web API supports convention-based routing. In this type of routing, Web API uses route templates to select which controller and action method to execute. \n\nAttribute-based routing: Web API 2 generally supports a new type of routing known as attribute routing. As the name suggests, it uses attributes to define routes. It is the ability to add routes to the route table via attributes.  Convention-based routing   Attribute-based routing  ",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "10. HOW to secure ASP.NET Web API?",
        "answer": "Web API has become key to programming web-based interactions. It can be accessed by anyone who knows the URL. Therefore, they have become targets for hackers. One needs to secure Web API by controlling Web API and by deciding who can and who cannot have access to Web API. There are basically two ways or techniques that make our Web API more secure. \n\nAuthentication: It is a process that helps to identify and check users by their credentials such as password, username, etc. To have access to the web API, firstly user credentials are needed to be passed in the request header. If user credentials are not passed into the request header, then the server returns 401 status code (unauthorized). The best authentication to be used is OAuth 2.0. \n\nAuthorization: It is a process that helps to decide whether or not a user has access to perform an action. Authorization filters are used to implement authorization.   Authentication:   Authorization:",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "11. What are Exception filters in ASP.NET Web API?",
        "answer": "Exception filter is generally used to handle all unhandled exceptions that are generated in web API. It implements IExceptionFilters interface. It is the easiest and most flexible to implement. This filter is executed whenever the controller method throws any unhandled exception at any stage that is not an HttpResponseExecption exception.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "12. Which .NET framework supports ASP.NET Web API?",
        "answer": ".NET Framework 4.0 generally supports the first version of ASP.NET Web API. After that, .NET Framework 4.5 supports the latest version of web API i.e., ASP.NET Web API 2.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "13. What is HttpConfiguration in Web API?",
        "answer": "It is considered as the main class that includes different properties with help of which one can override the default behavior of Web API. \n\nSome properties are given below:   DependencyResolver: It sets or gets a dependency resolver for dependency injection.\nServices: It gets web API services.\nParameterBindingRules: It gets a collection of rules for how parameters should be bound.\nMessageHandlers:  It sets or gets message handlers.\nFormatters: It sets or gets media-type formatters. DependencyResolver: It sets or gets a dependency resolver for dependency injection. DependencyResolver: Services: It gets web API services. Services: ParameterBindingRules: It gets a collection of rules for how parameters should be bound. ParameterBindingRules: MessageHandlers:  It sets or gets message handlers. MessageHandlers: Formatters: It sets or gets media-type formatters. Formatters:",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "14. Can we return View from ASP.NET Web API method?",
        "answer": "No, we cannot return the view from the ASP.NET Web API method. ASP.NET web API develops HTTP services that provide raw data or information. ApiController in ASP.NET MVC application only renders data that is serialized and sent to the client. One can use a controller to provide normal views.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "15. What is content negotiation in ASP.Net Web API?",
        "answer": "Content negotiation is basically a process of selecting the best representation from multiple representations that are available for a given response. It simply allows one to choose rather than negotiate content that one wants to get in response. It is performed at the server-side. In simple words, it chooses the best media type for matters to return a response to an incoming request.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "16. Difference between HTTP GET vs HTTP Post?",
        "answer": "HTTP (HyperText Transfer Protocol) simply manages request-response between client and server. It works as a request-response protocol between client and server. \n\nHTTP GET: This method is used to get information or data from a respective server at a specified URL.\n\nExample: \nGET/RegisterStudent.asp?user=value1&pass=value2\n\nHTTP POST: This method is used to send data or information to respective servers. \n\nExample:\nPOST/RegisterStudent.asp HTTP/1.1 \nHost: www.guru99.com  \nuser=value1&pass=value2 HTTP   HTTP GET   Example:    HTTP POST   Example:    HTTP GET HTTP POST\nIts parameters are included in the URL. Its parameters are included in the body.\nThis method is used to request data from specified resources and has no other effect. This method is used to send data to a server to create or update resources.\nIt carries a request parameter appended in the URL string. It carries request parameters in the message body that make it a more secure way of sending data or information from the client to the server.\nRequest method using GET is cacheable. Request method using POST is not cacheable.\nGET requests are less safe than POST. Post request is safer than GET.\nThere is a restriction on data type in GET method and only ASCII characters are allowed. There are no restrictions on data type in this method and binary data is also allowed.\nData is visible to everyone in the URL. Data is not displayed in the URL. It is present in the payload. HTTP GET HTTP POST\nIts parameters are included in the URL. Its parameters are included in the body.\nThis method is used to request data from specified resources and has no other effect. This method is used to send data to a server to create or update resources.\nIt carries a request parameter appended in the URL string. It carries request parameters in the message body that make it a more secure way of sending data or information from the client to the server.\nRequest method using GET is cacheable. Request method using POST is not cacheable.\nGET requests are less safe than POST. Post request is safer than GET.\nThere is a restriction on data type in GET method and only ASCII characters are allowed. There are no restrictions on data type in this method and binary data is also allowed.\nData is visible to everyone in the URL. Data is not displayed in the URL. It is present in the payload. HTTP GET HTTP POST HTTP GET HTTP POST HTTP GET HTTP POST Its parameters are included in the URL. Its parameters are included in the body.\nThis method is used to request data from specified resources and has no other effect. This method is used to send data to a server to create or update resources.\nIt carries a request parameter appended in the URL string. It carries request parameters in the message body that make it a more secure way of sending data or information from the client to the server.\nRequest method using GET is cacheable. Request method using POST is not cacheable.\nGET requests are less safe than POST. Post request is safer than GET.\nThere is a restriction on data type in GET method and only ASCII characters are allowed. There are no restrictions on data type in this method and binary data is also allowed.\nData is visible to everyone in the URL. Data is not displayed in the URL. It is present in the payload. Its parameters are included in the URL. Its parameters are included in the body. Its parameters are included in the URL. Its parameters are included in the body. This method is used to request data from specified resources and has no other effect. This method is used to send data to a server to create or update resources. This method is used to request data from specified resources and has no other effect. This method is used to send data to a server to create or update resources. It carries a request parameter appended in the URL string. It carries request parameters in the message body that make it a more secure way of sending data or information from the client to the server. It carries a request parameter appended in the URL string. It carries request parameters in the message body that make it a more secure way of sending data or information from the client to the server. Request method using GET is cacheable. Request method using POST is not cacheable. Request method using GET is cacheable. Request method using POST is not cacheable. GET requests are less safe than POST. Post request is safer than GET. GET requests are less safe than POST. Post request is safer than GET. There is a restriction on data type in GET method and only ASCII characters are allowed. There are no restrictions on data type in this method and binary data is also allowed. There is a restriction on data type in GET method and only ASCII characters are allowed. There are no restrictions on data type in this method and binary data is also allowed. Data is visible to everyone in the URL. Data is not displayed in the URL. It is present in the payload. Data is visible to everyone in the URL. Data is not displayed in the URL. It is present in the payload.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "17. What is CORS in Web API?",
        "answer": "CORS (Cross-Origin Resource Sharing) is basically a mechanism that allows one to make requests from one website to another website in a browser that is normally not allowed by another policy called SOP (Same Origin Policy). It supports secure cross-origin requests and data transfers among clients or browsers and servers. Here, cross-origin request means requests coming from different origins. CORS simply resolves the same-origin restriction for JavaScript. One can enable CORS for web API using the respective web API package or OWIN middleware.  ",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "18. Name method that validates all controls on page?",
        "answer": "Page.Validate()",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "19. What parameters can be passed in the URL of API?",
        "answer": "Context keys, documents keys, or anything that initiates API to hit the exact end-point are few parameters that one can pass in the URL to define the complete end-point.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "20. What is the use of DelegatingHandler?",
        "answer": "DelegatingHandler is used to develop a custom Server-Side HTTP Message Handler in ASP.NET Web API. It is used to represent Message Handlers before routing in Web API.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "21. Web API uses which library for JSON serialization?",
        "answer": "Json.NET library is used by Web API for JSON serialization.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "22. Explain method to handle error using HttpError in Web API?",
        "answer": "CreateErrorResponse is an extension method that can be used in Web API controller methods to return error codes and error messages. It creates an HttpError object and then wraps it inside an HttpResponseMessage object.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "23. How to unit test Web API?",
        "answer": "Using Web API tools like Fiddler, we can perform unit testing in Web API. Fiddler is basically a free debugging proxy for any browser that can be used to compose and execute various HTTP requests to Web API and check HTTP response. It is simply used for testing restful web services. It allows one to inspect and check both incoming and outgoing data to monitor and modify requests and responses before the browser receives them.  Below is given some setting that is needed to be done fiddler:\n\nFiddler – Compose Tab -> Enter Request Headers -> Enter Request Body and then execute.  ",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "1. Conclusion",
        "answer": "Web API is an extensible framework that serves us information from the server and is used for developing ASP.NET. It is totally based on Http and is easy to define, expose and consume in a REST-ful way. It is considered an ideal platform for developing RESTful applications on .NET framework. From the above Web API interview questions and answers, you can learn more about Web API, its importance, its benefits, etc.",
        "reference": "interviewbit.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "1) What is a Web API? / What do you understand by Web API?",
        "answer": "In Web API, API stands for Application Programming Interface. It is a framework that helps users to develop or build HTTP services that can be used by various clients, including browsers and mobile devices. For example, The ASP.NET Web API helps us to build these services on the .NET framework.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "2) Why use Web API? / Why is Web API preferred to use? / What is the reason behind using Web API?",
        "answer": "We have many other technologies similar to Web API, but there are several genuine reasons to use Web API.\nFor example:\nADVERTISEMENT\nWeb API provides us the ability to create non-SOAP-based HTTP services.\nWe can easily use it with HTTP verbs for Create, Read, Update and Delete operations.\nIt is very lightweight, and its lightweight architecture makes it ideal for small bandwidth devices such as smartphones.\nIt is based on HTTP and easy to define, expose and consume in a REST-ful way.\nIt provides an ability to select response output in either JSON or XML and support for Open Data (OData) protocol.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "3) Is it possible to use RESTful services using WCF? / Why is the use of Web API preferred over RESTful services?",
        "answer": "Yes, it is possible to use RESTful services using WCF. We can easily develop RESTful services with WCF, but two main reasons make users choose Web API instead of RESTful services.\nWeb API increases the TDD (Test Data-Driven) approach in the development of RESTful services.\nIf we want to develop RESTful services in WCF, you surely need many config settings, URI templates, contracts & endpoints.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "NET Web API has replaced WCF?",
        "answer": "No, it is not true at all that ASP.NET Web API has replaced WCF. ASP.NET Web API is another way to build non-SOAP-based services, i.e., plain XML or JSON string.\nWeb API is lightweight due to using HTTP only so. It cannot match the power and flexibility of WCF. Web API is perfect if you only need to use HTTP as your transport. But if you want to use a different protocol such as TCP or Named Pipes, you would have to use WCF.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "5) What is the main difference between Web API and WCF?",
        "answer": "WCF stands for Windows Communication Foundation. It is used for service-oriented application development supporting various transport protocols such as HTTP, TCP, MSMQ. The WCF clients must be able to understand XML. On the other hand, Web API is designed specifically for HTTP services, and due to its low-bandwidth, it supports non-SOAP services and most MVC features.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "6) What are the main advantages of using Web API?",
        "answer": "Following are the main advantages of using Web API:\nContent Negotiation\nSelf-Hosting\nOData\nFilters\nRouting\nModel Bindings",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "7) What are the differences between Web API and MVC?",
        "answer": "Following are the main differences between Web API and MVC (Model View Controller)\nMVC Web API\nMVC is an application design model used to create web applications with a front-end and controls and back-end processes. Web API is used to create HTTP services to interact with a variety of clients.\nWe can use the MVC to create web apps with user interfaces. We use Web API to develop HTTP services.\nIn the MVC design pattern, the web application returns a view as well as data. Web API returns the data only.\nMVC can only map requests to action methods. With Web API, we can map all requests to actions using HTTP verbs.\nMVC can return data only in JSON format. Web API can return data in JSON and XML, among other formats.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "NET framework supports Web API?",
        "answer": "The .NET framework version 4.0 and above versions support web API.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "9) What are the main return types supported in Web API?",
        "answer": "Following are the main return types of Web API controller action:\nVoid: It is used to return empty content.\nHttpResponseMessage: It is used to convert the response to an HTTP message.\nIHttpActionResult: It is used to internally call ExecuteAsync to create an HttpResponseMessage.\nOther types: It helps us to write the serialized return value into the response body.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "10) Which open-source library is supported by Web API for JSON serialization?",
        "answer": "Web API uses JSON.NET library for JSON serialization.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "11) What is the biggest drawback of \"Other Return Types\" in Web API?",
        "answer": "The biggest disadvantage of the \"Other Return Types\" in Web API is that it doesn't help us directly return an error code like a 404 error.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "12) What do you understand by Web API Routing?",
        "answer": "Web API Routing is a pattern matching just similar we do in MVC. All routes are registered in Route Tables.\nFor example:\nRoutes.MapHttpRoute(  \nName: \"ExampleWebAPIRoute\",  \nrouteTemplate: \"api/{controller}/{id}  \ndefaults: new { id = RouteParameter.Optional}",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "NET language?",
        "answer": "Yes, we can easily use ASP.NET Web API in the applications created using another language than .NET, but those applications must have access/support to the HTTP protocol.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "14) What do you understand by SOAP?",
        "answer": "The full form of SOAP is Simple Object Access Protocol. It is an XML message format used in web service interactions to interchange data. It facilitates users to send messages over HTTP or JMS. It is also an XML-based messaging protocol for exchanging information among computers.\nIn other words, we can say that SOAP is a messaging protocol used for interchanging data in a decentralized and distributed environment.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "NET Web Form?",
        "answer": "We can use the Web API with ASP.NET Web Form by performing the following three simple steps:\nFirst, create a Web API Controller.\nNow, add a routing table to the Application_Start method of Global. sax\nNow, we can make a jQuery AJAX Call to Web API method and get the data.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "16) How can we restrict or limit access to Web API to Specific HTTP Verb?",
        "answer": "We can easily restrict or limit access to an ASP.NET Web API method called using a particular HTTP method. In this process, attribute programming plays a crucial role.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "17) What do you understand by the RESTful Services?",
        "answer": "The full form of REST stands for the Representational State Transfer. Roy Fielding coined this term in 2000. RESTful is an architectural style for creating loosely coupled applications over HTTP. To make API to be RESTful, we have to follow the six constraints given below:\nClient and Server Separation: Clients and Servers are isolated in the RESTful services.\nStateless: REST architecture is based on the HTTP Protocol, and the clients can cache the server response, but no client context would be stored on the server.\nUniform Interface: It is used to allow a limited set of operations defined using the HTTP Verbs. For example, GET, PUT, POST, Delete, etc.\nCacheable: RESTful architecture allows the response to be cached or not. Caching improves performance and scalability.\nCode-On-Demand\nLayered System",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "18) What do you understand by exception filters?",
        "answer": "Exception filters are used to execute when exceptions are unhandled and thrown from a controller method. There may be several reasons for the exception. Exception filters implement the \"IExceptionFilter\" interface.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "19) What do you understand by TestApi in Web API?",
        "answer": "TestApi is a utility library of Web APIs. Using this library tester, developers can create testing tools and automated tests for a .NET application using data-structure and algorithms.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "20) Is it possible to return View from Web API?",
        "answer": "No, Web API does not return View, but they return the data. In Web API, APIController is used for returning the data. If you want to return a view from the controller class, you have to make sure you have used or inherited the Controller class.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "NET Web API?",
        "answer": "Parameter Binding is a process that specifies that when a Web API calls a method on a controller, it must set the values for the parameters.\nBy Default, Web API uses the following rules to bind the parameter:\nFromUri: If the parameter is of \"Simple\" type, the Web API tries to get the URI value. Simple Type includes.Net Primitive type like int, double, etc., DateTime, TimeSpan, GUID, string, any type which can convert from the string type.\nFromBody: If the parameter is of \"Complex\" type, the Web API only binds the values from the message body.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "22) How can you register exception filter globally?",
        "answer": "We can easily register exception filter globally by using the following code:\nGlobalConfiguration.Configuration.Filters.Add(new  \nMyTestCustomerStore.NotImplExceptionFilterAttribute());",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "23) What is the difference between REST and RESTful?",
        "answer": "Difference between REST and RESTful:\nREST RESTful\nThe full form of REST is REpresentational State Transfer. The term RESTful is written by applying REST architectural concepts called RESTful services. It is a completely new aspect of writing a web app. It mainly focuses on system resources and how the resource's state should be transported over HTTP protocol.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "24) What is Content Negotiation in Web API?",
        "answer": "Content Negotiation is the process of selecting the best representation for a given response from a set of various multiple representations available. Following are the two main headers that are responsible for the Content Negotiation:\nContent-Type: The content-type header is used to specify the server about the data; the server will receive from the client.\nAccept: Another way for Content Negotiation is to use Accept-Header. It is used to specify the format of data requested by the client from a server.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "25) Give an example to specify Web API Routing?",
        "answer": "Following is an example of Web API Routing:\nConfig.Routes.MapHttpRoute(  \nname: \"MyRoute,\"//route name  \nrouteTemplate: \"api/{controller}/{action}/{id}\",//as you can see \"API\" is at the beginning.  \ndefaults: new { id = RouteParameter.Optional }  \n);",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "NET Web API?",
        "answer": "The Media-Type formatter is an abstract class acting as a parent class of JsonMediaTypeFormatter and XmlMediaTypeFormatter. These two classes, JsonMediaTypeFormatter (which is used to handle JSON format) and XmlMediaTypeFormatter (which is used to handle XML format), are derived from the Media-Type formatter.\nThe Media-Type formatter classes are also responsible for serializing the response data in the client's format.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "27) What is the method to handle errors in Web API?",
        "answer": "Several classes are available in Web API, such as HttpError, Exception Filters, HttpResponseException, and Registering Exception Filters, etc., to handle errors.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "0?",
        "answer": "Following are the latest new features of ASP.NET Web API framework v2.0:\nAttribute Routing\nOpen Web Interface NET\nCross-Origin Resource Sharing\nExternal Authentication\nHttpActionResult\nWeb API OData",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "29) How can you restrict access methods to specific HTTP verbs in Web API?",
        "answer": "It is very easy to implement access restrictions in Web API with Attributes' help (like HTTP verbs). We can do it by defining HTTP verbs as an attribute to restrict access.\nFor example,\n[HttpPost]  \npublic void Method1(Class obj)  \n{  \n//Write logic here",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "30) What is Authorize Attribute? What is its use?",
        "answer": "Web API provides a built-in authorization filter known as Authorize Attribute. This filter is used to check whether the user is authenticated or not. If not, the user will see 401 Unauthorized HTTP Status Code.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "31) Is it possible to pass multiple complex types in Web API?",
        "answer": "Yes, we can easily pass multiple complex types in Web API by using the following two methods:\nUsing ArrayList\nUsing Newtonsoft array",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "32) What do you understand by basic HTTP Authentication?",
        "answer": "Basic HTTP Authentication is a mechanism that is used for user authentication. Here, users are authenticated through the service in which the client passes username and password in the HTTP Authorization request headers. The credentials are formatted as the string \"username:password,\" based on encoded.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "33) How can you pass an ArrayList in Web API?",
        "answer": "The following example shows the code how we can pass an ArrayList in Web API:\nArrayList paramList = new ArrayList();  \nCategory c = new Category { CategoryId = 1, CategoryName =\"MobilePhones\"};  \nProduct p = new Product { Productcode = 1, Name = \"MotoG\", Price = 15500, CategoryID = 1 };  \nparamList.Add(c);  \nparamList.Add(p);",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "NET MVC?",
        "answer": "In ASP.NET Web API, an HTTP request is used to map to the controller. The Web API framework uses a routing table to determine which action is to invoke.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "35) How can we handle an error using HttpError in Web API?",
        "answer": "In Web API, the HttpError method is used to throw the response body's error info. Along with this, the \"CreateErrorResponse\" method can also be used, which is an extension method defined in \"HttpRequestMessageExtension.\"",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "36) How can you register exception filter globally?",
        "answer": "We can use the following code to register an exception filter globally:\nGlobalConfiguration.Configuration.Filters.Add (new MyTestCustomerStore.NotImplExceptionFilterAttribute());",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "37) What do you understand by Exception handling in Web API?",
        "answer": "Exception handling is a technique used to handle runtime error in the application code. There are several ways that we can use to handle the error in ASP.NET Web API. Following is a list of some of them:\nHttpResponseException\nHttpError\nException Filters etc.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "38) What is Web API Versioning, and why is it used?",
        "answer": "Web API Versioning is a technique in which Web API is arranged to cope with the business changes, and the API will not impact the client that is using/consuming the existing API. As we know, multiple clients can consume the Web API at a time, so Web API versioning is necessary and required as the business grows, and business requirement changes with the time.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "39) How many ways are you to do Web API Versioning?",
        "answer": "Following are the several ways to do Web API Versioning:\nURI\nQuery String Parameter\nCustom Header Parameter\nAccept Header Parameter",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "40) What are the advantages of Web API over WCF?",
        "answer": "WCF services use the SOAP protocol while Web API never uses the SOAP protocol. That's why Web API services are lightweight since it doesn't use SOAP. It also reduces the data which is transferred to resume service. The biggest advantage of Web API is that it never needs too much configuration. Therefore, the client can interact with the service by using the HTTP verbs.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "41) What is the difference between MVC and Web API?",
        "answer": "Differences between MVC and Web API:\nMVC framework Web API\nThe MVC framework is used for developing applications that have a User Interface. WebAPI is used for developing HTTP services.\nIn the MVC framework, views are used for building a User Interface. Other apps can also call the WebAPI methods to fetch that data.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "42) Who can use or consume Web API?",
        "answer": "Any client which supports HTTP verbs such as GET, PUT, DELETE, POST etc., can use or consume Web API. Web API services don't need any configuration, so it is very easy to consume them by any client. Even portable devices like mobile devices can easily consume them, and it is surely the biggest advantages of this technology.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "43) What are the different HTTP methods used in Web API?",
        "answer": "Following are the different types of HTTP methods used in Web API. We can use them according to the requirements.\nGET: The GET method is used to retrieve the information from the respective server using a given URI.\nHEAD: The HEAD method is the same as the GET method, but it is used to transfer the status line and header section.\nPUT: The PUT method is used to update values, and it can replace all current resources with the uploaded content.\nPOST: A POST method is a request, and it is used to send data to the respective server.\nDELETE: The DELETE method is used to delete or remove all current resources given by a URI.\nOPTIONS: This method is used to describe the communication options for the target resource.\nCONNECT: The CONNECT method is used to establish a tunnel to the server identified by a given URI.\nTRACE: The TRACE method is used to perform a message loop-back test along the target resource path.\nNote: From the list of all the above methods, the GET, PUT, POST, and DELETE are the most popular methods. All methods are case-sensitive, and we must use them in uppercase.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "44) What do you understand by the HTTP Status Codes?",
        "answer": "The Response Header of each API response consists of an HTTP Status Code. The HTTP Status Codes are the three-digit integers that contain the server response. Here, each number specifies a meaning. The first digit of the Status-Code defines the class of response. According to this first number, the HTTP Status Codes are categorized into five types.\nFollowing is the list of HTTP Status Codes with their meaning:\nHTTP Status Codes Status Meaning\n1xx Informational It specifies that the request has been received and the process is continuing.\n2xx Success It specifies that the action was successfully received, understood, and accepted.\n3xx Redirection It specifies that we have to take further actions to complete the request.\n4xx Client Error It specifies that the request contains incorrect syntax or cannot be fulfilled.\n5xx Server Error It specifies that the server failed to fulfil a valid request.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "45) What are some commonly seen HTTP Status Codes?",
        "answer": "Following is the list of some commonly seen HTTP Status Codes:\n200 (Request is Ok)\n201 (Created)\n202 (Accepted)\n204 (No Content)\n301 (Moved Permanently)\n400 (Bad Request)\n401 (Unauthorized)\n403 (Forbidden)\n404 (Not Found)\n500 (Internal Server Error)\n502 (Bad Gateway)\n503 (Service Unavailable) etc.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "46) What do you understand by Internet Media Types?",
        "answer": "The Internet Media Type is a file identification mechanism on the MIME encoding system. It is also known as the \"MIME type.\" It has become the de facto standard for identifying content on the Internet.\nFor example, suppose we receive an email from a server with an attachment, then the server embeds the media type of the attachment in the message header. So, the browser can launch the appropriate helper application or plug-in.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "47) What is the difference between XML and JSON?",
        "answer": "Following are the differences between XML and JSON:\nXML JSON\nThe full form of XML is eXtensible Markup Language. The full form of JSON is JavaScript Object Notation.\nIt is a markup language like HTML and is designed to store and transport data. JSON is often used when data is sent from a server to a web page. It is also used to store and transport data.\nXML doesn't do anything, but it can store data in a specific format. JSON is a self-describing, easy-to-understand, lightweight format for storing and transporting data.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "NET Web API was introduced?",
        "answer": "The first version of ASP.NET Web API was introduced in .NET Framework 4. After that, all the later versions of the .NET Framework support the ASP.NET Web API.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "Web API?",
        "answer": "WCF vs. MVC vs. ASP.NET Web API:\nWCF MVC Web API\nWCF stands for Windows Communication Foundation. It is a framework that is used to build or develop service-oriented applications. MVC stands for Model View Controller. It is used to create a web application that returns both data and view (HTML). Web API is an open-source platform and framework used to create HTTP-based services that only return data and not view.\nIt is designed to exchange standard SOAP-based messages. MVC is used to facilitate the easy rendering of HTML. It supports most of the MVC features, which keep Web API over WCF.\nWCF can be consumed by clients who can understand XML. MVC is used to create a web app in which we can build web pages. The Web API framework is used to generate HTTP services that cover more clients by generating raw format data, for example, plain XML or JSON string.\nWCF supports a variety of transport protocols such as HTTP, TCP, Named Pipes or MSMQ, etc. JSONit will return JSONResult from the action method. Web API creates simple HTTP services that render raw data.\nWCF ships out with the .NET Framework. All requests are mapped to the respective action methods. Web API returns XML or JSON to the client.\nWCF service is good for Message Queue, duplex communication, one-way messaging. We can return a view from MVC. In an ASP.NET MVC application, requests are mapped to Action Methods. All requests are mapped to actions using HTTP verbs.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "50) How can we unit test the Web API?",
        "answer": "We can use the Fiddler tool to unit test the Web API. Follow the steps given below and do the setting in the Fiddler tool:\nCompose Tab -> Enter Request Headers -> Enter the Request Body and execute.",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "51) How can you return JSON from Web API Service irrespective of the Accept header value?",
        "answer": "We can easily return JSON from Web API Service irrespective of the Accept header value by removing the XmlFormatter from the Register() method of WebApiConfig.cs file, which is present inside the App_Start folder. Use the following piece of code to remove XmlFormatter completely. It will always return data in JSON format irrespective of the Accept header value in the client request.\nconfig.Formatters.Remove(config.Formatters.XmlFormatter);",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    },
    {
        "question": "52) What is the difference between Controller and ApiController?",
        "answer": "Controller is used to rendering our normal views.\nExample:\npublic class TweetsController : Controller {  \n  // GET: /Tweets/  \n  [HttpGet]  \n  public ActionResult Index() {  \n    return Json(Twitter.GetTweets(), JsonRequestBehavior.AllowGet);  \n  }  \n}  \nApiController is used when we have only to return data that is serialized and sent to the client.\nExample:\npublic class TweetsController : ApiController {  \n  // GET: /Api/Tweets/  \n  public List<Tweet> Get() {  \n    return Twitter.GetTweets();  \n  }  \n}",
        "reference": "javatpoint.com",
        "role": "web-api"
    }
]